Kyle Duesler

1733 Morgan Ave St. Paul, MN 55116 kyle.duesler.09@gmail.com (612)800-4561

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kyle-duesler-1a24b8277/https://github.com/kduesler

Summary

Creative, resourceful, and enthusiastic web developer with solid abilities in highly collaborative work environments and problem-solving. Drawing on experience with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, with knowledge of the best practices in web design and user experience.

Relevant Skills

Web Development

• HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, SQL, React, MongoDB

Spanish Language

Fluent in written and spoken Spanish

Projects

Quote Generator | https://kduesler.github.io/Quote-Generator

- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Summary: Generate random quotes with backgrounds that correspond to each category of quotes.

Employee Tracker | https://github.com/kduesler/Kvle-Employee-Tracker

- Tools: MySQL, Node.js
- Summary: Create a content management system, that allows users to view and interact with the information stored in the database.

Weather Dashboard | https://kduesler.github.io/Kyle-Weather-Dashboard/

- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Summary: Use this weather dashboard to view the 5-day forecast of any city you search.

Education

Full Stack Development Certification, University of Minnesota May 2023

Bachelor of Arts, Bethel University – St. Paul, MN

December 2013

Major: Elementary Education

Minor: Spanish

Relevant Experience

4th-8th Grade Math and Science Teacher

Bdote Learning Center

July 2019-June2021

- Plan and implement all 4th-8th grade math and science lessons
- Develop and encourage a positive growth mindset in all aspects of learning
- Use appropriate and effective classroom management skills to provide a healthy learning environment

Site Interpreter/Tour Guide

April 2018 - July 2019

Gibbs Farm and Museum

- Lead guided tours of a historic site including Dakota and pioneer life
- Study and continue to learn about life in the 1800's in Minnesota
- Implement day camp activities involving farm, art, and history lessons

Third Grade Teacher

August 2015-June 2017

Aurora Charter School, Minneapolis, MN

- Develop yearly goals, plans, and activities for the school year
- Prepare and implement weekly plans and activities while following year at a glance
- Provide opportunities for social and emotional growth

Kindergarten Long-Term Substitute Spanish Immersion Teacher September 2014 - December 2014 Little Canada Elementary School, MN

- Prepare and implement grade level lessons and activities for Spanish Immersion Program
- Maintain contact with students' parents or guardians via newsletters, email, phone, and conversation
- Provide students with a comfortable, safe, and healthy learning atmosphere
- Develop and implement supplemental after-school learning activities